(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ロマンスの不祥事に重なり、消してあげる
Overlapping with romance scandals, I'll erase them for you.
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
作詞：ナナホシ管弦楽団 作曲：岩見 陸
Silv President
Lyrics: Nanahoshi Orchestra Composition: Riku Iwami
先生、私が大統領になったら、人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
Teacher, when I become president, I'll exile any woman who messes with someone else's man!
先生、私が大統領になったら、「いやただの友達だよ」ってごまかすやつはヘソから電気を流します
Teacher, when I become president, anyone who tries to play it off with "No, we're just friends" will have electricity shot through their belly button!
ダダダ大統領！
Pre-pre-pre-president!
えっと、ときせき、センセーショナル、クローズアップ
Heart-throb, sexy, sensational close-up!
ダダダどんくらい？
Ho-ho-ho-how much?
やるぜ、徹底的にリサーチだ
Let's do it! Conduct a thorough investigation!
だいだいだい嫌い
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you
しょうがない、クズは病気でバイバイバイ
It can't be helped. Scumbags, bye-bye-bye because of their sickness!
ケセパサ人生
A fluffy life
何もないけどサバキタイ、でしょ？
There's nothing there, but I want to judge them, right?
ダダダ大統領になったらね
When I become pre-pre-pre-president
まずは君を捕まえる
First, I'm going to capture you
濡れたタオルで洗いたて
With a freshly washed, wet towel
吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything!
誰ですか、あの女
Who is that woman?
誰ですか、そうですか
Who is she? Oh, I see.
ロマンスの不祥事に重なり、消してあげる
Overlapping with romance scandals, I'll erase them for you.
シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
S'il vous plaît-ple-ple-president!
先生、私が大統領になったら、「ただの仕事の付き合いだよ」ってやつは、二度と働けなくしてやりまーす
Teacher, when I become president, anyone who says, "We're just business acquaintances," will never be able to work again!
先生、いや火力、向こうが強引でさぁ、って男の口にはネジを流し込んで、固めてやりまーす
Teacher, "She was really pushy!" A man who says that will have screws poured into his mouth and then be set in stone!
ミミミ密着！
Cl-cl-cl-close contact!
まるで鈍感気取り、スキャンダラス
Acting like you're oblivious, scandalous!
マママ待った！
Wai-wai-wait!
不干渉なしのスクープね
A scoop without any interference!
愛はない、理由じゃない
There's no love, that's no reason
悪くないのにね、ハイハイハイ
Even though you're not in the wrong, right? Yes, yes, yes.
軽薄なの、イケしゃあしゃあ
Frivolous, with that brazen look
何もないとか、あり得ない、でしょ？
That "nothing happened"? That's impossible, right?
ダダダ大統領になってもね
Even if I become pre-pre-pre-president
多分君は、捕まらない
You probably won't be caught
しらっとすっとぼけて
Casually playing dumb
のらりくらり、かわすのね
Slipping away so noncommittally!
テストですか、こんばんは
Is this a test? Good evening.
本気ですか、そうですか
Are you serious? Oh, I see.
情熱コア、不注意で
Passionate core, through carelessness
遺伝子も、消してしまいたい
I want to erase your very genes!
ちょっと！みんな浮気してんじゃないでしょうね。
ちゃんと見ててよね！
Wait a second! You guys aren't cheating on me, are you?
You'd better keep your eyes on me!
ダダダ大統領になったらね
When I become pre-pre-pre-president
マジで君を捕まえる
I'm seriously going to capture you
濡れたタオルで洗いたて
With a freshly washed, wet towel
吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything!
どどどどこですか、今あんた
Whe-whe-whe-where are you now?
見つけちゃった、バレちゃった
Found you! You've been found out!
不実には不条理
Absurdity for unfaithfulness
さよなら、代わりに銃声
Farewell, and a gunshot in its place
シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
S'il vous plaît-ple-ple-president!
はい、というわけで！
Yes, so!
みんな見えてますかー？
Can everyone see me?
今日は紫咲シオン3周年ということで！
Today is my, Murasaki Shion's, 3rd anniversary!
えー、ちょっと息が切れてるんだけど...
Um, I'm a bit out of breath, but...
今日紫咲シオン3周年ということでね！
Since today is Murasaki Shion's 3rd anniversary!
いっぱい歌って、お喋りして、
I'll sing a lot, chat,
ゲストの方も、えー、いるとか、なんと、か...
and I heard there might be guests... or something like that.
ぜひみんな楽しみに、楽しんで見てください！
Please look forward to it and enjoy the show!
イェーイ！
Yay!
というわけで、
So,
次の曲行きます！
on to the next song!
みんな、いっぱいツイートしてね！
Everyone, please tweet a lot!
あぁ、素晴らしき世界に今日も乾杯
Ah, cheers to this wonderful world again today
街に飛び交う笑い声も
The laughter flying through the city
見て見ぬふりしてるだけの作りもんさ
Is just a fabrication that I pretend not to see
気が触れそうだ クラクラするほどのいい匂いが
It's driving me crazy, a scent so good it makes me dizzy
ツンと刺して鼻の奥 目を覚ます本能のまま
Pierces deep into my nose, waking up my instincts
今日は誰の番だ？
Whose turn is it today?
この世界で
In this world...
何ができるの？ 僕には何ができるの？
What can I do? What can I possibly do?
怪物 作詞・作曲：Ayase
Monster | Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
ただその真っ黒な目から 涙こぼれ落ちないように
Just so tears don't fall from those pitch-black eyes
願う未来に 何度でもずっと食らいつく
I'll keep biting onto the future I wish for, over and over
この間違いだらけの世界の中
In this world full of mistakes
君には笑ってほしいから
I want you to be able to smile
もう誰も傷つけない 強く強くなりたいんだよ
I don't want to hurt anyone anymore, I want to become strong, so strong
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself
素晴らしき世界は今日も安泰
This wonderful world is peaceful again today
街に渦巻く悪い話も
Even the bad stories swirling in the city
知らない知らないふりして目を逸らした
I pretended not to know, not to know, and looked away
正気の沙汰じゃないな 真面目に着飾った行進
This is madness, a parade of people seriously dressed up
鳴らす足音が弾む 行き先は消えない消えない
The sound of footsteps echoes, the destination won't disappear, won't disappear
味が染み付いている
The flavor is soaked in
裏側の世界
The world on the flip side
清く正しく生きること
Living purely and correctly
誰も悲しませずに生きること
Living without making anyone sad
はみ出さず真っ直ぐに生きること
Living straight without straying
それが間違わないで生きること？
Is that what it means to live without mistakes?
ありのまま生きることが正義か
Is living as you are 'justice'?
騙し騙し生きるのは正義か
Is living a life of deception 'justice'?
僕のあるべき姿とはなんだ
What is the way I should be?
本当の僕は、何者なんだ 教えてくれよ
Who am I really? Tell me!
教えてくれよ
Tell me!
今日も答えのない世界の中で 願ってるんだよ
Even today, in a world with no answers, I'm wishing
不器用だけれど
Clumsy as I am
いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
Because I just want to keep laughing with you forever
跳ねる心臓が 体揺らし叫ぶんだよ
My beating heart shakes my body and screams
今こそ動き出せ
Now is the time to start moving
あぁ、弱い自分を 何度でもずっと食らいつく
Ah, I'll keep biting onto my weak self, over and over
この間違いだらけの世界の中
In this world full of mistakes
君には笑ってほしいから
I want you to be able to smile
もう誰も泣かないよう 強く強くなりたいんだよ
So that no one cries anymore, I want to become strong, so strong
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself
ただ君を守るそのために
Just for the sake of protecting you
走る 走る 走るんだよ
I'll run, I'll run, I'll run
僕の中の僕を超える
Surpassing the 'me' inside of me
はい、というわけで、
Yes, so,
2曲目は「怪物」でした！
the second song was 'Monster'!
可愛い曲からのカッコいい曲ということで、
From a cute song to a cool one,
ちょっと温度差が激しいかなと思いますが、
the difference might be a bit drastic, but...
本当にありがとうございます、みんな！
Thank you all so much!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
みんな、コメント見えてるよ、ちゃんと。
Everyone, I can see your comments clearly.
「カッコいい」だって。嬉しい！
'Cool,' you say. I'm so happy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めっちゃ緊張してるよ、めっちゃ緊張してるよ、
I'm super nervous, I'm super nervous,
バカたれが。
you idiots.
はい、というわけでですね、
Yes, and so,
次は、
next...
ここからはなんと、スペシャルゲスト凸待ち...
from here, believe it or not, a special guest call-in waiting...
いーくーよー！
Here we go!
はい。というわけで、えー
Alright. And so, uh...
先ほどね、掛け声をした通り、スペシャルゲスト凸待ちとなっております。
As I announced just now, we're having a special guest 'totsumachi'.
お気づきの通り、なんと背景が、あのライブの素晴らしいステージから、
As you may have noticed, the background went from that wonderful live stage...
なんと真っ青の、真っ青の深海みたいな背景になっちゃったんですが、ブルーバックということで
...to this deep blue, deep sea-like background, which is actually a blue screen.
今からシオンの3周年を祝いに3人のホロメンが凸をしてきてくれるそうです。
Starting now, three Hololive members will be joining us to celebrate Shion's 3rd anniversary.
誰だろうね、みんな。
I wonder who they are, everyone.
誰だろうね。知らないよね、みんなね。そうだよね。
I wonder who. You don't know, right? Yeah, of course.
あの告知のムービーにもちょっとシルエットだけ載せたけど、わかんない。誰だ！
I showed some silhouettes in the announcement video, but I don't know. Who could it be?!
というわけで、なんとみんなそれぞれシオンのために背景を書いてきてくれたそうなので
Anyway, it seems like everyone drew a background just for Shion.
その背景をベースにポーズを撮るのでみんなたくさんスクショしてください。
I'll be posing with those backgrounds, so please take lots of screenshots.
ということで衣装もね、あの通常衣装でやっていこうかなと思います。
So, I'll be doing this in my default outfit.
みんなたくさん、みんなたくさんカメラマンになってお写真を撮るという、えー、そんな素敵なコーナーとなっております。
It's a wonderful segment where everyone becomes a photographer and takes photos.
ちなみにシオンはまだみんながどんな背景を書いてきてくれたか知らないんだよ。見てないんだよ。
By the way, I still don't know what kind of backgrounds everyone drew. I haven't seen them yet.
だからちょっとね、ドキドキしております。
So I'm a little nervous.
というわけでですね、早速一人目の凸待ちが、凸が来たそうなので
Well then, it looks like our first guest is here.
繋いでみましょう！
Let's connect with them!
ドキドキ。
So excited.
はーい！
Hiiiii!
あー！
Ah!
どーもー！
Hellooo!
この声は！
This voice is...!
シオン先輩、三周年おめでとうございます！
Shion-senpai, happy 3rd anniversary!
ありがとー！るしあちゃん！見えてる？
Thank you! Rushia-chan! Can you see me?
見えてる見えてる！
I can see you, I can see you!
超かっこよかったよ！
You were super cool!
やったー！ありがとー！
Yay! Thank you!
見ててくれてありがとー。
Thanks for watching.
おめでとう。どーも。
Congratulations. Hello.
ありがとー！
Thank you!
潤羽るしあです。
I'm Uruha Rushia.
自己紹介。
Self-introduction.
え、え、え、今日ね、え、
Um, today, uh,
シオン先輩、背景どんなのだと思う？
Shion-senpai, what do you think the background is like?
えー、さすがにるしあちゃん可愛いからさ。
Well, since Rushia-chan is so cute...
ね、大好きだもん、るしあちゃんのこと。
You know, I love you, Rushia-chan.
あらー！
Oh my!
見てるの、実はこっそりね。
I've actually been watching you secretly.
こっそり？
Secretly?
こっそり見てるんだけど。
I've been watching secretly.
もっと可愛い私を出してきてほしい。
I want you to show an even cuter version of me.
あー、じゃあちょっとね、ここでシオン先輩にるしあが用意した背景見てほしいと思うんだけど。
Ah, then I'd like Shion-senpai to see the background I prepared.
うん、ちょっと見てよ。
Yeah, take a look.
ドロン！
Ta-da!
ちょっ、るしあ、えっ、ちょっと待って。
Wait, Rushia, uh, hold on a second.
顔、埋まってるんだけど。何これ。
The faces are buried. What is this?
ちょ、あれ？せっかくの顔が。
Wait, what? The precious faces...
ちょ、るしあと顔、隠してあるんだけど。
Wait, Rushia's face is hidden.
え、何これ、ここに顔があるのね。
Eh, what is this? There are faces here.
待って、これ、すごいね、るしあちゃん見て。人、いるよ。
Wait, this is amazing, Rushia-chan, look. There are people!
ちょっと待って。スイカ、これ何？これ、木？
Wait a minute. Watermelons, and what's this? A tree?
あ、これね、うん。
Ah, that's...
これ何だと思う、シオン先輩。
What do you think this is, Shion-senpai?
え、これ何だろうね。
Eh, I wonder what it is.
あ、分かった分かった。これ、持つんじゃないの？こうやって。違う？
Ah, I get it, I get it. I'm supposed to hold this, right? Like this? No?
そうよ！
That's right!
正解！
Correct!
でかいね、枝ね、ちょっと待って。
It's a huge branch, wait a sec.
え、でかっ！
Whoa, it's huge!
シオンちゃんと同じくらいあるよ、るしあちゃん。
It's about as big as you, Shion-chan.
やばっ、シオン先輩のさ、これ、顔くれた。わかった。このスイカ野郎、スイカ野郎をぶっ叩くってことね。
Geez, Shion-senpai's face... I get it. I'm supposed to smash this watermelon jerk, right?
そうそうそう！あの、待って！その前のは割っちゃダメです。生きてるから。その後ろのやつを割るんだよ。
Right, right, right! But wait! Don't split the one in front. That one's alive. You split the one behind it.
あ、これね、そういうこと。
Ah, I see. That's the one.
そっちな。あ、これ違うの？
That one? Oh, this isn't it?
あ、これ違うの。
Ah, this isn't it.
あ、これを、こう！
Ah, this one, like this!
割れちゃうから。そ、えいって、なんか、そういうショット撮ってほしいと思って。
It'll split. Yeah, 'ei!', like that. I wanted to take a shot like that.
え、どう？いい感じ？見て。
Eh, how is it? Looking good? Look.
いい感じ、いい感じ！
Looks good, looks good!
めっちゃいい感じだけど。
Looks really good.
めっちゃいい感じだよ。
It looks really good.
ちょっと海女さんっぽくして、シオン先輩、海女、海女さんっぽく。
Try acting like an 'ama-san' (diver), Shion-senpai, like a diver.
海女さん？
A diver?
セクシー。
Sexy.
どう？どう、るしあちゃん？
How's this? How is it, Rushia-chan?
あ、ちょうどそこに二つあるじゃん、でっかいのが。
Ah, you have two big ones right there.
わはは！
Wahahaha!
お、これ、ちょっともしかして。
Oh, maybe these...
やば、やば、どう？
Wow, wow, how's this?
あ、いいね。可愛い可愛い。
Ah, nice. Cute, cute.
可愛い！
Cute!
ダイナマイトボディが。
That dynamite body...
え？
Eh?
あ、あ、もう一回もらっていい？ちょっと早くさ。スクショタイム！
Ah, ah, can I get that one more time? Quickly. Screenshot time!
撮ってよ！
Take the photo!
あ、可愛いね。カシャカシャ、いいね、いいね、いいね。
Ah, cute. Click-click, nice, nice, nice.
いいですか？
Is this okay?
カシャカシャカシャ、可愛い！
Click-click-click, so cute!
え、ちょっと海も泳いでみよう。
Eh, let me try swimming in the sea too.
海泳ご。泳ご。
Swim in the sea. Let's swim.
あ、いい、いい、シオン先輩、海女、海女。あ、海泳ぐ、行きます。
Ah, good, good, Shion-senpai, diver, diver. Ah, swimming in the sea, here I go.
バシャバシャバシャ。
Splash splash splash.
うわー、バシャバシャ！
Whoa, splash splash!
奥にキズ、奥にキズ！シオンちゃんほら！
Kizu's in the back, Kizu's in the back! Shion-chan, look!
混ざってきた。奥にキズいる。
He's getting mixed in. Kizu's in the back.
おい、おい、キズ！
Hey, hey, Kizu!
キズ！
Kizu!
海キズ。
Sea Kizu.
いいよ、いいよ、いいよ。
Nice, nice, nice.
という感じだった。
That's how it went.
え、めっちゃ可愛い。エモかった。
Eh, that was so cute. It was moving.
ね、海女、ちょっとアップってできないのかな。
Hey, can we do a close-up of the diver?
あ、確かに。アップできるのかな。
Ah, true. I wonder if we can do a close-up.
どうなんだろう。近く、近づけないのかな。
I wonder. Can't we get closer?
あ！
Ah!
あ、いいじゃん！
Ah, that's perfect!
これじゃん、るしあちゃん。
This is it, Rushia-chan.
これだ！
This is it!
これだよ！
これだ！
This is it!
あ、これじゃん。
Ah, this is it.
これだ。
This is it.
あ、いいよ、可愛い。セクシー。
Ah, nice, cute. Sexy.
あ、セクシーセクシー。あ、いいね。
Ah, sexy, sexy. Ah, nice.
あ、いいね、いいね。キズ、いじめてくるわ。
Ah, nice, nice. I'm gonna go bully Kizu.
やめなよ！
Stop it!
いい感じ。
Looking good.
やってきた、やってきた。
I did it, I did it.
やったやった、やっつけた、やっつけた。
I did it! I beat it, I beat it!
めっちゃいい感じ。
Looking very good.
めっちゃ笑顔で。
With a big smile.
よかった。
Good.
超いい。ね、後ろにさ、サーフィン乗ってる人もいるんだよ。
Super good. Look, in the back, there's even someone surfing.
待って、これ本当にこれ、サーフィンじゃなくね？
Wait, isn't this really NOT surfing?
これさ、え、これさ、タイヤ付いてるけどこれ本当？
This, uh, this has tires, is it real?
スノーボードとかじゃない、スケボーじゃないこれ？
It's not a snowboard, isn't this a skateboard?
いや最新式のさ。
No, it's the latest model.
そう、あの海のさ、サーフィンの。
That, the sea, surfing one.
最近のサーフィン。
Recent surfing.
あ、そうなんだ。最近のサーフィン、タイヤ付いてるんやな。
Ah, I see. Recent surfing has tires attached.
え、どうかな？上手く撮れたかな？
Eh, how was it? Did it turn out well?
上手く撮れたよ、みんな。どう？
It turned out well everyone. How is it?
めっちゃ可愛いからね。
Because it's very cute.
ほら「スケボーじゃね？」って言ってるよ、ルシアちゃん。
Look, they're saying "isn't it a skateboard?", Rushia-chan.
スケボー...
Skateboard...
おかしいな。
That's strange.
でもめっちゃ楽しかったね。
But it was very fun.
上手く撮れたんじゃないかなって思うよ、ルシアは。
I think it turned out well, Rushia.
そうやね、ルシアも。
Yeah, me too.
うん、ありがとう。
Yeah, thank you.
退散しようかな。
Should I leave now?
え、本当に、シオン先輩、おめでとう３周年！
Ah, really, Shion-senpai, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
また遊ぶわ。
Let's play again.
遊ぶ、遊ぶ。いっぱい遊ぼうね。
Let's play, let's play. Let's play a lot, okay?
遊ぼうね。バイバイ！
Let's play. Bye bye!
バイバイ！ありがとう！
Bye bye! Thank you!
うん、このあとも頑張ってね！
Yeah, good luck for the rest too!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、ルシアちゃんでした。
And so, that was Rushia-chan.
これ頑張ってさ、いらすとやで素材集めてね。
Thinking about how she worked hard gathering materials from Irasutoya.
頑張ってくれたって考えると心が温まりますね、これ。
Thinking about how she worked hard for me, it warms my heart.
というわけで、ダイナマイトボディのシオンでした。どうですか、みんな？
And so, this was Shion with the dynamite body. How is it everyone?
写真撮れたかな？
Were you able to take photos?
というわけでですね、次の...
And so, the next...
次の方の準備が満端ということで、早速凸をかけて...
The next person's preparation is complete, so I'd like to jump into the call right away...
かけていきたいと思います。
I'd like to start it.
え、次の方はこちらです！ドドン！
Eh, the next person is this one! Ta-da!
もぐもぐ...
Mogu mogu...
おかゆー！
Okayu!
シオン、３周年おめでとう。
Shion, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary.
おかゆ、いつ結婚するの？
Okayu, when are we getting married?
まあまあまあ...
Well, well, well...
え、まあ、もしかしておかゆさ、今日さ、ウェディング...
Eh, "well"...? Wait, Okayu, is today the wedding...
ウェディング結婚式とかじゃない、背景？
Wedding ceremony... isn't the background like a wedding?
あ、すごい、よく分かったね。
Ah, amazing, you noticed.
今日は、そう、シオンと結婚式を挙げるなら...
Today, yes, if I were to have a wedding ceremony with Shion...
...ここかなっていうのをちょっと選んできたからね。
...it would be here, I thought, so I chose this.
じゃあ僕が用意した背景はこちらです。
Well then, the background I prepared is this one.
お。
Oh.
え、ちょっと待って、おかゆ？おかゆ？ちょっと待って、え？
Wait a minute, Okayu? Okayu? Wait a minute, eh?
でもほら見て。
But look, see.
あ、アイアイ傘も書いてあるでしょ？
Ah, there's even a sharing-an-umbrella drawing, right?
え、おかゆはさ、こういうところで結婚式挙げたいってこと？
Eh, Okayu, you mean you want to have a wedding ceremony in a place like this?
まあ、シオンと挙げるならここかな？
Well, if I'm having it with Shion, I guess here?
え、本当言ってる？本当のやつそれ？
Eh, are you serious? Is that for real?
いや僕がシオンに嘘なんてついたことないでしょ。
No, I've never lied to you, Shion, have I?
え、だから待って、「うわーん出してよ」って書いてあるよ。
Eh, but wait, it says "Waaah, let me out"!
まあまあまあ、これなんかね、プリクラっぽく...
Well, well, well, this is like a purikura...
あ、可愛いシオン。あ、可愛い。
Ah, cute Shion. Ah, cute.
可愛い、もっと近づいて、もっと。もっと、もっと！
Cute, get closer, more. More, more!
もっと近づいて、もっと近づいて！
Get closer, get closer!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いシオン。
You're so cute, Shion.
お、もっと行けるのかな？行けないのかな？これマックスなのかな？
Oh, can I go further? Or not? Is this the limit?
多分マックスかも。
Probably the limit.
え、可愛い、あ、ここマックスみたいだね。
Eh, cute. Ah, looks like this is the limit.
え、可愛い、なんかピンプリみたいで可愛いよ。
Eh, cute. It's like a solo-purikura, cute.
いやでもなんか悲しくなってきたけど。心が寂しくなってきたよ、おかゆ。
No, but I'm starting to feel sad. My heart is feeling lonely, Okayu.
でもほら、アイアイ傘見てごらん。
But look, look at the umbrella drawing.
あ、ほら。おかゆ、シオン。あ、可愛い、おかゆシオン。
Ah, look. Okayu, Shion. Ah, cute, Okayu Shion.
めちゃくちゃ可愛いシオン。
You're so cute, Shion.
猫いるじゃん、ここに。あ、おかゆ！これおかゆ！
There's a cat here. Ah, Okayu! This is Okayu!
よしよしおかゆ。
Good girl, Okayu.
うん、これ僕だよ。よしよしおかゆ。
Yeah, this is me. Good girl, Okayu.
ほら、シオンのさ、悲しい顔見せてよ。悲しい顔。
Hey, show me your sad face, Shion. Sad face.
え、悲しい顔行くよ？
Eh, sad face? Here I go.
ええーん！ええーん！出して、ここから出して。
Eeeeh! Eeeeh! Let me out, let me out of here.
あ、可愛い！でも結婚式なんだよね、おかゆ。何で泣かすの？
Ah, cute! But it's a wedding ceremony, right, Okayu? Why are you making me cry?
あ、感動して泣いちゃったってこと？ああ、そういうこと。
Ah, you mean I started crying because I was moved? Ah, I see.
そういうことだよ、おかゆ。
That's how it is, Okayu.
いや可愛いな。あ、よかった。え、じゃあ今日結婚ってことだねこれ、実施。
No, so cute. Ah, good. Eh, so we're getting married today, practically.
そうだよ。
That's right.
本当？
Really?
やっぱこういうとこがいいじゃん。
After all, a place like this is good, right?
笑ってるじゃん！笑ってる！
You're laughing! Laughing!
いやいやほら、天気もいいからな、窓から日射してるし。
No no, look, the weather is good too, sunlight is coming through the window.
本当だ、天気いい。ここ？
True, the weather is good. Here?
ね、結婚日和だね、ほら。
Right, it's a perfect day for a wedding, look.
なんかスポットライトみたいだね、ほら。
It's like a spotlight, look.
そう、シオンはやっぱね、僕たちのアイドルだからさ。
Yeah, because Shion is, after all, our idol.
そうね、そうね。でも寂しいけどね、ちょっと。
Right, right. But it's a bit lonely.
いつまでもこういう、こういうところにいてほしいってこと、おかゆは？
You mean you want me to stay in a place like this forever, Okayu?
え、そういう感じね。
Eh, so that's it.
いやいや、でもさ、好きな子はさ、自分だけのものにしたいって気持ちはあるでしょ？
No no, but, you know the feeling of wanting the person you like all to yourself, right?
ああ、本当！それならもう、もう喜んでここにいるおかゆ。じゃあ、結婚しようね。
Aaa, really! If that's the case, I'll gladly stay here, Okayu. Well, let's get married.
よかった。ここ待ってるからね、来てくれるの。隣に。
Glad it was here. I'll be waiting for you to come. To my side.
隣にね。待ってるね。
To your side. I'll wait.
いや、たまにはね、シオンにこういうなんか脱獄ライフを味わってほしかったんだよね。
No, occasionally, I wanted Shion to experience this kind of "prison break" life.
あ、本当に？よかった。したことないでしょ？
Ah, really? Good. You've never done it before, right?
ないよ。でもおかゆあるじゃん、そう言えば。
No. But Okayu has, come to think of it.
僕はもうしょっちゅうだよ、牢屋にぶち込まれることなんて。
I'm frequently thrown into jail.
え、じゃあ今度は一緒に牢屋...
Eh, then next time together in jail...
一緒に行こうね。
Let's go together.
一緒に行こうね。おかゆ待ってるからね。
Let's go together. I'll be waiting for you, Okayu.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いやマジ可愛いよ。
No, seriously, you're cute.
ありがとう、おかゆ。
Thank you, Okayu.
はい。じゃあシオン。
Okay. Well, Shion...
頑張ってね、続きも。まだまだ。
Good luck with the rest. There's still a lot to go.
頑張る！歌めっちゃ可愛かったからね。
I'll do my best! Your song was so cute.
やった！ありがとう。
Yay! Thank you.
ありがとう、おかゆ。
Thank you, Okayu.
バイバイ。またね。
Bye-bye. See ya.
ちょっとさ、思う。
I've been thinking...
結構こういうとこね、おかゆが好きなら、それは別に構わんのだけどね。
If Okayu likes this kind of place, I don't really mind...
ここでも全然ね。
Doing it here is fine too.
なんかでもちょっと寂しいよね、これが結婚式ってなるとね。
But it's a bit lonely if this is the wedding venue.
ちょっと寂しい、孤独は感じるよね。
It's a bit lonely. You feel the solitude.
はい。というわけで、おかゆありがとうございました。
Right. So, thank you very much, Okayu.
次が最後ですね。
The next one is the last one.
最後はこの方です。どうぞ！
The final guest is this person. Here you go!
ちょっと！どういうことなんですか！？
Wait! What on earth is going on here!?
ちょっと！あくあ！
Hold on! Aqua!
お誕生日おめでとう、シオンちゃん。
Happy birthday, Shion-chan.
出た、それ。え、今日誕生日…そうだよ今日誕生日だよ。
There it is. Wait, today is my birthday... that's right!
おめでとう。
Congratulations.
今日誕生日。やっぱね、もう3年目の誕生日ってことでね。
It's my birthday. Well, it is my 3rd anniversary birthday.
確かにそれはそうだけど、ちょっとさ、許せないんだけど。どういうことさっきの？
That's true, but wait, I can't let this slide. What was that earlier?
ずっと聞いてましたけども。え？おかゆとは結婚したがるし。
I've been listening the whole time. You want to marry Okayu?
いやいやいや。おかゆはあそこがいいって結婚式挙げたいんだって。
No, no, no. Okayu said she liked it and wanted to have the wedding there.
そうやって騙されてるよ、シオンちゃん。
You're being tricked, Shion-chan.
え？え？
What? Huh?
じゃあドンマイ！ドンマイシオンちゃん。
Well, don't mind it! Don't mind it, Shion-chan.
おかゆはあそこが好きなんだ、あそこで結婚式挙げ…僕の理想だよって言ってたもん。
Okayu likes that place. She said "Having a wedding there is my ideal."
あ、そうなの？騙されてるよ、あくあ。
Oh, is that so? You're the one being tricked, Aqua.
ドンマイ、ドンマイあくあ。
Don't mind it, don't mind it, Aqua.
いやね、ちょっとね、そんなかわいそうなシオンちゃんに、今日はちょっと私がね、ちょっと用意してきた…
Well, for such a poor Shion-chan, I've prepared something for today...
え、なに、なに？
Eh, what is it? What?
あのね。シオンちゃんさ、プリクラとか撮ったことある？
You know, Shion-chan, have you ever taken purikura?
あんまないｗ
Not really, lol.
任せて。プリクラ博士の私からすると、今回は、シオンちゃん寂しい？
Leave it to me. As a purikura expert, Shion-chan, are you lonely?
そうだよ、寂しいって言ってた…
Yeah, I was saying I was lonely...
私がその寂しさをちゃんと埋めてあげるから。
I'll make sure to fill that loneliness for you.
あ、本当？わかった。
Oh, really? Okay.
私が用意した背景、どうぞ！
Here is the background I prepared!
デデン！デデン！おお！
Ta-da! Ta-da! Oh!
チャリで来た。
Came by bike.
は！？これ誰！？
What!? Who are these guys!?
いややっぱりね、ネットのやっぱプリクラっていう、まあ文化？
Well, you know, the internet's purikura culture...
その中で、やっぱ一番古の、やっぱ古から伝わる、伝説のね、やっぱプリクラっていうのがあって。
Amongst that, there's an ancient, legendary purikura passed down from long ago.
チャリで来たっていうやつなんだけど。
It's the one called "Came by bike."
待って、背景。
Wait, the background...
シオンちゃんポーズがあって、右腕をこう前に。この人たちと同じように。こう！
Shion-chan, there's a pose. Put your right arm forward like this, just like them. Like this!
グーで？
With a fist?
そう！でちょっと斜めになって。
Yes! And stand a bit diagonally.
こう？こっち？
Like this? This way?
そっちじゃない、えっとね、ちょっと体を斜めに向ける感じ。
Not that way, um, try turning your body diagonally.
あ、そうそうそう！こんな感じ！はいはいはい！いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
Ah, yes yes yes! Like that! Yes, yes! Looking good!
皆撮って！皆撮って！
Everyone, take a picture! Take a picture!
これ完成！
It's complete!
え、どう？シオンちゃん。
So, what do you think, Shion-chan?
これ誰、これ誰？
Who is this? Who are they?
友達。シオンちゃんの友達。
Friends. They're Shion-chan's friends.
これ、女の子だよね。
These are girls, right?
女の子だよ、シオンちゃん。ツインテール付いてるじゃん。
They're girls, Shion-chan. Look, they have twintails.
やっぱね、シオンちゃん3周年ってことでね、幸せになってほしいから、友達いっぱい用意したよ。
Since it's your 3rd anniversary, I want you to be happy, so I prepared many friends.
すごい似合ってる。すごい可愛い。友達がいるから孤独じゃない。
It suits you so well. So cute. You're not lonely because you have friends.
本当に？いい、本当？シオンちゃん。
Really? Is it okay? Really, Shion-chan?
やったー可愛いって。おめでとうシオンちゃん。
Yay, they're saying I'm cute. Congratulations, Shion-chan.
ありがとう、なんか温かい気持ちになった。
Thank you. I feel warmed up now.
よかったー。頑張ろう、あくあ。
Glad to hear that. Let's do our best, Aqua.
本当に？心が温まった。ありがとう。
Really? My heart is warmed. Thank you.
チャリで来た。
Came by bike.
もうさ、私たちさ、3年も一緒にいるからさ、あの、トークできない。
You know, we've been together for 3 years, so we've run out of things to talk about.
確かにお話しすることもなくなっちゃうよね。
True, we do run out of topics to discuss.
まあでも「チャリで来た」があるから大丈夫だよ。
But we have "Came by bike" now, so it's okay.
チャリで来たのおかげで今絡まってる。
Thanks to "Came by bike," we're interacting now.
じゃあまた今度ね。湊あくあでした。
See you later. Minato Aqua signing off.
バイバイ。ありがとう。
Bye-bye. Thank you.
はい、というわけで。
Well then.
なんか寂しかったな、結局。
It was kind of lonely in the end.
でもほら友達3人いたし、4人で今プリクラ撮ることなんてね。
But look, I had three friends, and taking a purikura with four people is rare.
だからな本当に。嬉しかったよな。来てくれた。
I'm serious. I'm so happy they could make it.
というわけで...
And so...
えー、というわけでですね、るしあちゃん、おかゆ、あくあ、ありがとうございました。
So, Rushia-chan, Okayu, and Aqua, thank you so much.
今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming today!
みんな、ちゃんと写真撮った？みんな写真撮った？
Everyone, did you take screenshots? Did you all take photos?
シオンさ、初めて見たからさ、今さ、すごいびっくりしてんだけどさ...
It's Shion's first time seeing this, so I'm actually really surprised right now...
...みんなちゃんと写真撮りましたか？
...but did you all take photos?
写真撮った？みんな。良かった。あの、こっちだ、これ！
Did you take photos? Everyone? Good. Um, this way, this!
ツイートしてください。紫咲シオン3周年記念でね、いっぱいツイートしてください。
Please tweet about it. Tweet a lot with #MurasakiShion3rdAnniversary.
トレンド1位なりたいな。
I want to hit number 1 on trending.
やっぱほら、1位、なりたいな！
I really want to be number 1!
というわけで、ここからはライブパート、行くぞー！
Alright, it's time for the live performance! Here we go!
好きになって もっと 私を見て もっと
Fall in love with me more, look at me more
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って 恋しちゃってください
Make a heart and please fall in love with me
やれること 何でもします
I'll do anything I can
NGなしで 体当たり挑戦
No NGs, I'll give it my all
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ ふざけんな誰より分かってるし
Anti-comments I find while vanity searching, don't mess with me, I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫 ここに立てば みんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand here, everyone is with me
行くよ！
Here we go!
好きになって もっと 私を見て もっと
Fall in love with me more, look at me more
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love
虜にする もっと 夢を見せる もっと
I'll captivate you more, show you more dreams
楽しんでて 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Have fun on this special night full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
みんな！見えてるかー！
Everyone! Can you see me!
ファンサしちゃうぞー！
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も 書いてください
Please write me letters too
何度も読んで 宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
Scandals are still a bit early, but
裏切りません 宣言しときます
I declare that I won't betray you
嫉妬嫌がらせには負けない ふざけんな実力で勝ってやる
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment, don't mess with me, I'll win with my own skills
だからやめない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
So I won't quit, I'm a sore loser, I'm right here
行くよ！
Here we go!
拳上げて もっと 汗をかいて もっと
Raise your fists more, sweat more
恩返しは 愛のこもったモノビームで
I'll repay you with a beam full of love
大歓声 もっと まだまだね もっと
Give me a big cheer, more, it's not enough
受け止めてね 愛のこもったわがままソング
Please accept my selfish song full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
はぁ...終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Sigh... the end is near, it's lonely
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
I'm having fun, but I feel like crying
次も 次も また会えるよね
Next time and the time after, we can meet again, right?
約束！
Promise!
まだまだこれからだよ！
There's still more to come!
みんな、ちゃんと見てるかー！
Everyone, are you watching!
優しさに溢れている言葉も 心ない誰かの言葉さえも
Both words overflowing with kindness and even the heartless words of some...
必要（い）るんだ 必要（い）るんだ 強く成ろう
...are necessary, they're necessary, let's become strong
好きに叫べ もっと 楽しんじゃえ もっと
Shout as much as you like, enjoy it more
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, I hope this becomes a special day
共に歌おう ずっと 共に歩もう ずっと
Let's sing together forever, let's walk together forever
合言葉は とびきりのL・O・V・E
The password is an extraordinary L-O-V-E
好きになって もっと 私を見て もっと
Fall in love with me more, look at me more
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love
虜にする もっと 夢を見せる もっと
I'll captivate you more, show you more dreams
楽しんでて 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Have fun on this special night full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
はい！というわけで、ありがとうございました。ファンサでした。
Alright! And with that, thank you very much! That was "Fansar".
実はですね、みんな気付いた方もコメントチラチラ見てたけどいるかなーと思うのですが、
Actually, I saw some comments from people who noticed, and I wonder if anyone else did,
掛け声の方をですね、あの、2期生の方にお願いしました。
but I asked the 2nd generation members to do the call-and-response.
2期生のみんながね、合いの手してくれてるんだよ。ありがとう！
The 2nd gen girls provided the background calls. Thank you!
そう、チョコ先生と、スバルちゃんと、あくあと、あやめちゃん。
Yes, Choco-sensei, Subaru-chan, Aqua, and Ayame-chan.
そう、4人だね。しおんいないからね、4人だね。
Right, there were four of them. Since I'm here, there are four of them.
そう、本当にありがとうございました。みんな気付いたかな？
Yes, thank you all so much. Did everyone notice?
どう、気付いた？あ、「やっぱり」って言ってる。ほら気付いたでしょう。そう、そうなんだよ。
How was it, did you notice? Oh, someone's saying "I knew it". See, you noticed! Yes, that's right.
というわけでファンサでした。ちょっと疲れた...っ水、水飲みます。
And so, that was "Fansar". I'm a bit tired... I'm gonna drink some water.
えっと水飲みます、すみません。
I'll drink some water, excuse me.
あー...喉...え、すごい！ステージすごい、みんな！
Ah... my throat... Whoa, this is amazing! The stage looks incredible, everyone!
うおー、めっちゃ紫色じゃん。紫色パレットなんだけど。
Whoa, it's so purple. It's like a purple palette.
というわけで、ありがとうございました。続いての曲にいきたいと思います。
Anyway, thank you very much. I'd like to move on to the next song.
ゴー！
Go!
レディメイド
Lady Made
ロンリー ロンリー 夜べない寂しさに
Lonely lonely, in the loneliness of the night
頬杖ついてるようじゃ変われない
If you're just resting your chin on your hands, you won't change
分かってんだよ お利口（おめーりー）
I know, you good-for-nothing
ありふれたモブなんだって
That you're just an ordinary background character
認めてないならいっそ 腐るまで叫んで
If you don't admit it, then just scream until you rot
いっそ顔出せば赤裸々に 本音ばかりじゃ生きられない
If you just show your face, reveal everything; you can't live on true feelings alone
どっかに転がって不尽生が きっとお似合いだなぁ
A rolled-up, inexhaustible life would surely suit you
大人になれば溶け込んで
When you grow up, you'll blend in
観念と愛情で踊るのさ
Dancing with ideas and affection
1 2 3 で弾けたんだ
It popped with a 1 2 3
固定観念ぶっ飛ばして どうだい どうだい
Blowing away fixed ideas, how's that, how's that?
なくなる前か
Before it disappears?
レディメイドの琴線に
To the heartstrings of the ready-made
歪みかけてノイズ混じり 後悔 後悔
Distorting, mixed with noise; regret, regret
やめて黙っていろ
Stop it, just be quiet
舌に乗った苦い感情ばかり隠して
Hiding only the bitter emotions on your tongue
だって だって 言葉飲み込めばほら
But, but, if you swallow your words, see
いい子になるわよなんて 顔色伺ってんだよ お利口（おめーりー）
"You'll be a good girl," staring at your face, you good-for-nothing
歪みだすラブなんだって
That it's a love that's starting to warp
有象無象のブランド 身につけて威張って
Wearing the brands of the masses and acting proud
舌鳴らせば 決まり文句 不適合者は魔女狩りさ
If you click your tongue, the cliché; non-conformists are a witch hunt
あなたの代わりはどこにだっている
Your replacement is everywhere
きっと楽なんだなぁ
It must be easy
社会の外側はどうですか？
How is it outside of society?
観念も愛情もクソ喰らえ
To hell with ideas and affection
1 2 3 で砕いたんだ
It shattered with a 1 2 3
既成概念の中に立って 能無い 能無い
Standing inside established concepts; incompetent, incompetent
混ぜて笑っていな
Mix it and keep laughing
レディメイドの円舞に
To the ready-made waltz
機械仕掛けのノイズ弾き 問題 問題
Plucking mechanical noise; problem, problem
解らず待っていな
Wait without understanding
塞ぎ込んだ黒い感情ばかり隠して
Hiding only the black emotions that were blocked up
ねえほら また始まった
Hey, see, it's started again
理屈ばかりで飽きたんだ
I'm tired of all the excuses
大人にだけはなりたくなんかないさ
I just don't want to become an adult
天邪鬼なほっといて
Leave the contrary me alone
私、私気付いたのさ
I, I've realized it
1 2 3 で弾けたんだ
It popped with a 1 2 3
固定観念ぶっ飛ばして どうだい どうだい
Blowing away fixed ideas, how's that, how's that?
なくなる前か
Before it disappears?
レディメイドの琴線に
To the heartstrings of the ready-made
歪みかけてノイズ混じり 後悔 後悔
Distorting, mixed with noise; regret, regret
やめて黙っていろ
Stop it, just be quiet
ぶっ壊して飛ばした
I smashed it and sent it flying
既成概念真っ赤に塗って
Painting conventional ideas bright red
NO NIGHT DO NIGHT 本当は泣いていた
NO NIGHT DO NIGHT, I was actually crying
レディメイドの円盤に
On a ready-made disc
ゲートかけてノイズ弾き飛ばせ
Set the gate and blast away the noise
問題問題 研ぎ澄ましていたの
Problem, problem, I was sharpening it
舌に乗った苦い感情ばかりを隠して
Hiding only the bitter emotions on my tongue
やんないんじゃない できないんだ (ホイ！)
It's not that I won't, it's that I can't (Hoi!)
お時間ごろし
Killing time
巷で噂のダメ天使
The rumored no-good angel in town
ダメなとこは満点
A perfect score in being no-good
幸せパワーで補っていく
Making up for it with happiness power
それ予定さ
That's the plan
ねぇ 見栄えも もっともっと
Hey, more and more about my looks
あなたに気にしてほしい
I want you to care
だけど注目されすぎたらビビる
But if I get too much attention, I get scared
ディスコに逃げ
And flee to the disco
天使のリングの点滅は
The flashing of my angel ring
切れかけてるけど
Is about to cut out
見方を変えれば
If you look at it differently
これもアイデンティティさ
This is also my identity
なんて強がりさ 本当は
What a bluff, honestly
曖昧な愛の感情を
The vague feelings of love
あなたと探したいの
I want to find with you
ねぇ ダメダメダメダメな私を
Hey, love me, the no-good, no-good me
愛してね (イェー)
Love me (Yeah!)
体外の衝動に無気力な
An angel who's lethargic
天使ですが (はい！)
Towards most impulses (Hai!)
ドキドキドキドキをあげるよ
I'll give you heart-pounding excitement
あなたには
For you
ちゃんと見ていてくれるなら
If you watch me properly
やるよ多分 (はい！)
I'll do it, maybe (Hai!)
ダダダダダメ天使は
Are no-good angels
ダダダダダメですか
No-good?
だけどもう 私はいいか
But well, I'm okay now
やんないんじゃない できないんだ (ホイ！)
It's not that I won't, it's that I can't (Hoi!)
テストでいい点とりたい
I want to get good grades on tests
でも頭がちっとも追いつかない
But my head can't keep up at all
日曜日だって早起きしたい
I want to wake up early even on Sundays
深夜のネトゲがやめられない
But I can't stop late-night online gaming
やる気がないとかそんなんじゃないな
It's not that I lack motivation
やる気があってもできない性分
It's just my nature that I can't do it
しょうがないなって許してよ
Forgive me, saying 'it can't be helped'
エンジェルリングを頬張りながら
While stuffing my face with angel rings
天使の翼は使ってない
I don't use my angel wings
飛ぶの怖いから
Because flying is scary
本気を出したら飛べますが
I could fly if I got serious
みたいな面はしている
I'm making a face like that
そんなハリボテの裏側に
Behind that paper-thin facade
隠した愛の感情が
The hidden feelings of love
あなたに笑ってほしいの
I want you to smile
ねぇ ダメダメダメダメな私でいいですか
Hey, is it okay if I'm the no-good me?
実際は一切の自信もないような
Actually, I'm an angel who doesn't have
天使ですが
A shred of confidence
グルグルグルグルと巡る
Going round and round and round
頭の中では
Inside my head
あなたのことばかり
I'm thinking only
考えてるんだ
About you
ダメダメダメダメな私を 愛してよ
Love me, the no-good, no-good me
もらった愛で飛ぼうと思うよ
I think I'll fly with the love I received
天使だから (はい！)
Because I'm an angel (Hai!)
ドキドキドキドキをあげるよ
I'll give you heart-pounding excitement
あなたには
For you
もっと好きになってくれるなら
If you love me more
やるよ多分 (はい！)
I'll do it, maybe (Hai!)
ダダダダダメ天使は
Are no-good angels
ダダダダダメですか
No-good?
だけどもう 私はいいか
But well, I'm okay now
やんないんじゃない できないんだ (ホイ！)
It's not that I won't, it's that I can't (Hoi!)
や、でも努力はします
B-but, I'll make an effort
はい というわけで
Alright, so...
ちょっとね 途中からね
Actually, partway through...
イヤホンが取れちゃったけど 頑張って最後まで歌いました
My earphone came out, but I did my best to sing until the end
はい というわけで みんな ダダダダ天使でした
Alright, so everyone, that was 'Da Da Da Da Tenshi'
その一個前の曲が レディメイドでした
The song before that was 'Ready Made'
というわけで 二曲通して ありがとうございました
So, thank you for listening to those two songs
続いてはですね 皆さん
Next up, everyone...
重大発表とはなんだろうと思ってるんじゃないですか？
Aren't you wondering what the big announcement is?
なんと今ここで、1つ目の重大告知をしたいと思います！イエーイ！
Well then, right here and now, I'd like to make the first major announcement! Yay!
なんとこの度、紫咲シオン初の...
Well then, Shion Murasaki's first ever...
ジャーン！オリジナル曲、出ます！イエーイ！
Ta-da! My original song is coming out! Yay!
みんな待ってたのではなかろうか、ドーン！ということで、ドーン！
I'm sure you've all been waiting for this, boom! And here it is, boom!
はい、メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットという曲です。
Yes, the song is called "Mage of Violet."
この曲はですね、かいりきベアさんに書き下ろしていただきました。
This song was written specifically for me by Kairiki Bear-san.
あの本当にね、かいりきベアさんの曲、全部可愛くて大好きなんですよ。
I really love all of Kairiki Bear-san's songs because they're so cute.
だから書き下ろしてもらえて、とても嬉しいです。
So I'm really happy he wrote one for me.
イラストは、のう先生に描いてもらいました。
As for the illustration, I had Nou-sensei draw it.
はい、というわけでこの後ですね、歌うんですが、えー...
Yes, so, I'm going to sing it after this, but, um...
この後の22時、配信終わりの22時にプレミア公開として、歌とMVが公開されます！
At 22:00 after this, as soon as the stream ends, the song and MV will be premiered!
みんなそちらも絶対見てくださいね！本当に絶対ですよ！今見てる人全員見てくださいね！
Everyone, please be sure to watch that too! I mean it! Everyone watching right now, please watch it!
というわけで、そろそろですね、いきたいと思います。
So, it's about time we got started.
オリジナル曲のメイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットです。
My original song, "Mage of Violet."
メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット
作詞・作曲：かいりきベア 編曲：すりぃ
Mage of Violet
Lyrics/Composition: Kairiki Bear Arrangement: Surii
嫌い放題 見てないで
Stop looking at me with such dislike
ウラパッパッパラリラ 踊れよ
Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, come on and dance
魔界学校の優等生
The honor student of the demon world school
華やかな我が儘 讃えよ
Praise my glamorous selfishness
無い無い場（バー）でこっち向いて
In this non-existent place, look this way
淑やかな未来を 咲かせよ
Make a graceful future bloom
次第相まって 昂まって
Gradually blending together and rising up
溜まったパワー放て 黒魔術
Release your pent-up power, black magic
セイノの毒に集えよ
Gather round for the poison on count of three
闇に震えろゲルベロス
Tremble in the darkness, Gelberos
切に響く言葉は
The words that resonate deeply
ブチギレ発狂パラダイス
Are a snapping, insane paradise
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Flash! Reach the deepest part of your heart
これからも私の元で
From now on, stay by my side
不思議な力 撃ち放って
Shoot out a mysterious power
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
The whole world will end up smiling too
ウラパッパッパラリラ 歌えば
Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, if you sing it
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together for life, right?
嫌い放題 してないで
Stop doing whatever you want with your dislikes
生っから疎らば 踊れよ
Born sparse, come on and dance
視界外目 逸らさないで
Don't look away from me
今はただ離れて 構い出
For now, just stay away and start caring
ニャニャ待って あっち向いて
Nya nya, wait, look over there
今はまだ心の準備を
I'm still getting my heart ready
期待さえ切って 固まって
Even cutting off expectations and freezing up
ウラパッパ動け 黒魔術
Ura-pa-pa, move it, black magic
我に続け 今宵よ
Follow me tonight
闇を破れメシアよ
Break through the darkness, Messiah
映れ化け物その名は
Be reflected, monster, whose name is...
眠りの端境（はざかい）パラダイス
The threshold of sleep paradise
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Flash! Reach the deepest part of your heart
白黒つけてあげるから
Because I'll make everything clear-cut
不思議な力 振りかざして
Brandish a mysterious power
みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
Everyone will end up smiling together
ウラパッパッパラリラ 歌えば
Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, if you sing it
一生一緒かもね
Maybe we'll be together for life
ヒラリヒラリと紫に染まって
Fluttering, fluttering, dyed in purple
これからもあなたの元で
From now on, by your side
奇跡の呪文 解き放って
Unleash a miracle spell
咲かせる笑顔の花を
And make the flowers of smiles bloom
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Flash! Reach the deepest part of your heart
これからも変わらないままで
From now on, staying just as we are
不思議な力 ほら宿って
Look, a mysterious power dwells within
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
The whole world will end up smiling too
ウラパッパッパラリラ 歌えば
Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, if you sing it
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together for life, right?
絶対一生一緒だよね
Absolutely together for life, right?
はい、というわけで、今聴いていただいたのがメイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットでした。はい。
Yes, so, what you just heard was "Mage of Violet." Yes.
え、めちゃめちゃ素敵な曲だと思うんですが、
I think it's a really wonderful song,
どうでしょうか、皆さんいかがでしょうか？
what do you think? How is it, everyone?
このあとですね、MVも公開されるので、
The MV will also be released after this,
よかったら見てください。よかったらじゃねえ、
so please watch it if you'd like. Actually, not "if you'd like,"
よかったらじゃねえよ。絶対見ろよ！
I shouldn't say "if you'd like." You MUST watch it!
絶対見ろよ！はい！ということで、
You definitely have to watch it! Alright, so,
あの22時からですね、プレミアム公開の枠、
well, at 22:00, the premiere slot,
実は「？？？」で立てさせて頂いたんですが、
I actually set up a slot with "???" as the title,
それがオリジナル曲のMVのプレミアム公開の枠となっております。
and that's the premiere slot for my original song's MV.
見てね！絶対見てよ！
Watch it! Be sure to watch it, okay!
はい！ということで、告知第2弾！
Alright! Now, for the second announcement!
なんと！3周年記念グッズ！イェーイ！
What! 3rd Anniversary Goods! Yay!
みんなね、きっと気づいてたと思うけど、
I'm sure everyone probably already noticed,
3周年記念グッズが出ます！
but 3rd Anniversary Goods are coming out!
あの、ということでですね、あの、
Um, and so, well,
活動3周年記念ということで、
to celebrate my 3rd anniversary,
8月17日今日、このあとですね、発売されます。
they'll be released today, August 17th, after this.
えっと、概要欄にですね、多分URLも貼ってあると思うので、
The URL is probably in the description box,
ぜひそちらから皆さんこのあと見てください。
so please take a look at it from there later.
記念グッズ3種ということで、まず、
There are three types of commemorative goods, starting with,
ブランケット！
A blanket!
はい、ブランケットと紫咲シオンのボイス入り目覚まし時計。
Yes, a blanket and a Murasaki Shion voiced alarm clock.
いや、これ後ほど詳しく説明しますので。
I'll explain more about this later.
ランダムアクリルキーホルダーが1種。
And one type of random acrylic keychain.
ということでこれがフルセットですね。
And all of these come in the full set.
じゃあブランケットから見ていこうと思います。
Let's take a look at the blanket first.
どうぞ！
Here it is!
はい、デデン！
Yes, ta-da!
はい、なんとイラストはTam-U先生、シオンのママが、
The illustration is by Tam-U-sensei, Shion's mama,
描き下ろし新しいイラストを描いてくれました。
who drew a brand new illustration for this.
可愛い！
So cute!
ブランケットの方は、大きいから、
The blanket is big,
フルので、イラストを全部写ってる。
so it shows the entire illustration.
すごい可愛いです。全部写ってるからね。
It's really cute. You get to see the whole thing.
目覚まし時計の方は切り取られてるんですけど。
The alarm clock version has a cropped version.
そう、めちゃめちゃ可愛いんだよ、これ。
Yeah, it's just so incredibly cute.
なんと皆さんお気づきの通り、コンセプトは睡眠です！
And as you might have noticed, the concept is sleep!
コンセプトは睡眠、えー、なんでですかね？
The concept is sleep... hmm, why is that?
本当に！なんで睡眠なんですかね？
Really! Why sleep?
なんかね、シオンと言えば寝るみたいな、
You know, there's this bad rumor that,
良くない噂が立っておりますけどね。
when you think of Shion, you think of sleeping.
はい、ということでブランケットね、めちゃめちゃ可愛いし、
Anyway, the blanket is super cute,
めちゃめちゃ大きいので、ぜひ皆さんこれを手に入れてください。
and it's very large, so please make sure to get one.
はい、次どうぞ！
Alright, next please!
はい！紫咲シオンのボイス入り目覚まし時計！
Yes! Murasaki Shion voiced alarm clock!
これです！皆さんこれすごいですから、本当に！
This is it! Everyone, this is really amazing, seriously!
これはですね、オリジナルボイス5種類収録しました。
I've recorded five different original voices for this.
はい、撮り下ろしました。その5種類ですね、
Yes, I recorded them specifically for this alarm clock.
この目覚まし時計のために。実はこれ、あの、
The five voices recorded... Actually, this...
鳴るじゃないですか、目覚まし時計って。
You know how alarm clocks ring?
それシオンの声なんです！
Well, that ring is Shion's voice!
シオンの声で朝が迎えれるという、えー素晴らしいものとなっております。
It's a wonderful item that lets you wake up to Shion's voice.
色も可愛いよね、紫色で。
The color is cute too, it's purple.
なんかちょっと淡い感じのパステル紫みたいな色で、
It's like a soft pastel purple,
とても可愛いのではないのでしょうか。
isn't it very pretty?
これでですね、あの仕事に行く方も学生の方も、
With this, whether you're going to work or you're a student,
これで毎朝起きて頂けたら、
if you wake up to this every morning,
なんという目覚め、目覚めをね、迎えれるか、
what a way to wake up that would be.
起きてください本当に。
So please wake up, seriously.
光栄ですよ、こんなこと。
It's an honor to be able to do this.
はい、ということで5種類あるのでですね、ランダムで再生されます、多分。
So, since there are five types, they'll play randomly... probably.
ランダムで再生されると思います。
I think they'll play in a random order.
これめちゃめちゃすごいから、みんな手に入れてください。
This is really great, so everyone please get one.
これもイラストTam-U先生です。可愛いよね、これ。
This illustration is also by Tam-U-sensei. It's cute, isn't it?
もう最高でしょ！最高なんだよ、これ！
It's the best! This is just the best!
はい、次デデン！
Alright, next, ta-da!
はい！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー1種ということで、
Yes! One type of random acrylic keychain!
これはですね、むーらん先生がイラストを描いてくれました。
Muran-sensei drew these illustrations.
4種類あります。
There are four different kinds.
これ実はシオンがちょっとやってみたかったことで、
This is actually something I've wanted to try doing,
今回あの、やらせて頂きました。ありがとうございます。
so I was allowed to do it this time. Thank you so much.
はい。ランダムのアクリルキーホルダー、まあめちゃめちゃそのままじゃないかい。
Yes. Random acrylic keychains... well, it's exactly what it says.
ランダムのアクリルキーホルダーなんですけど、イラストがですね、
They're random acrylic keychains, and the illustrations feature
通常衣装とアイドル衣装、あと、
my standard outfit, my idol outfit, and,
これも通常衣装なんですけど、
this one is also my standard outfit,
上にですね、塩っ子がいるんですよ。これみんなのことですね。
but there's a Shiokko on top. That's all of you.
あの、これむーらん先生がシオンのリスナーさんのことを、
Um, Muran-sensei created an image character
あのイメージキャラクターを作ってくれたから今回むーらん先生にですね、
representing Shion's listeners, so I asked Muran-sensei
お願いして、あのイラスト描き下ろして頂きました。ありがとうございます。
to draw these new illustrations. Thank you so much.
あとゴスロリ衣装！
And the gothic lolita outfit!
これは可愛い、猫ちゃん！ニャー！
This one is cute, a kitty cat! Meow!
はい。むーらん先生がですね、担当してます。
Yes. Muran-sensei was in charge of these.
ということでこちらもぜひ皆さん、あの全部揃えてください。あの、
So, please make sure to collect all of these as well. Um,
揃えろとは言いませんが、
I'm not telling you that you HAVE to collect them all,
揃えてください。ぜひ！
but please collect them. Please do!
はい、ということで以上がフルセットの内容となっております。
Alright, so those are the contents of the full set.
ということで、フルセット購入特典として、Tam-U先生描き下ろしポストカードがついてきます。
And as a bonus for purchasing the full set, you'll receive a postcard with a new illustration by Tam-U-sensei.
はーい、いえーい！
Hi, yay!
今回はですね、前回の誕生日の時は直筆サインを...
This time, while I think I did hand-signed ones...
...やったと思うんだけど、今回は箔押し複製サインのメッセージ入りポストカードということで
...for my last birthday, this time it's a foil-stamped reproduction signed postcard with a message.
メッセージの方は届いてからのお楽しみとなっています。
The message is a surprise for when it arrives.
これも全部買うよね、みんな。
You're all going to buy this too, right?
全部買うでしょ、全部買って見てください。
You'll buy it all, won't you? Please buy it all and take a look.
飾ってください一緒に。よろしくお願いします。
Please display it. Thank you.
可愛いでしょ、キラッキラなんだよ、サインとメッセージが。はい。
It's cute, isn't it? The signature and message are all sparkly. Yes.
というわけで、以上の3つ...
So, those are the three...
...3つとは思えないぐらいのボリュームだけど、そう、ポストカード抜いて3つのグッズでした。
...it's hard to believe it's just three, yes, excluding the postcard, there were three items.
これね、みんな絶対手に入れてください。概要欄からどうぞ、よろしくお願いします。
Everyone, please make sure to get these. Check the description box. Thank you.
というわけで、この後ですね、すぐ...っていうか、今21時52分ということで
So, after this, soon... well, it's 21:52 right now.
この後22時からオリジナル曲のMVが公開されます！
The MV for my original song will be released at 22:00!
メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット
Mage of Violet
絶対、絶対見てください。
Please, please watch it.
一生のお願いをここで使うかもしれないぐらいのお願いです。お願いします。
This is a request so big I might be using up my one life-long favor here. Please.
はい、ということで『メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット』、ぜひね見てください。素敵に仕上がっておりますので。
Yes, so please watch 'Mage of Violet'. It turned out wonderful.
はい、というわけで、みんな今日はシオンのね、3周年を祝っていただいてありがとうございました。
Alright, so thank you everyone for celebrating Shion's 3rd anniversary today.
思ってたよりちょっと早く終わっちゃったね、シオンが早口で喋りすぎたわ。ちょっと。
It finished a bit earlier than I thought. I talked way too fast. Just a bit.
みんなありがとうね。コメントちゃんと見えてるからね。
Thank you everyone. I can see your comments clearly.
みんなよろしくね。グッズも、オリ曲もたくさん聴くし、グッズもすぐ購入する。はい、よろしくお願いします。
Take care, everyone. Listen to the original song a lot, and buy the goods right away. Yes, please.
ということで、3周年ありがとうございました！4周年の紫咲シオンも、どうぞよろしくお願いします！
So, thank you for the 3rd anniversary! Please continue to support Shion Murasaki in her 4th year as well!
これからも頑張ります！みんなありがとう！じゃあね、バイバーイ！
I'll keep doing my best! Thank you everyone! See ya, bye-bye!